

Phone: 7906302115, Email: amanjain111569@gmail.com

LinkedIn HackerRank

Diligent IT enthusiast with 3-years Computer Science degree and 1+ year of industry experience. As a dedicated problem solver, I display an explicit skill in JavaScript, it's supporting libraries/frameworks and Web Development. Through my experience at TCS, I have gained further hands-on experience in the industry.

EXPERIENCE

MAY 2021 - AUGUST 2022

GRADUATE TRAINEE, TATA CONSULTACNY SERVICES (TCS)

- As a graduate trainee, industry professionals taught me a variety of cutting-edge technologies, including JavaScript, Java, Git, SQL, Python. In the development phase, business decision-making and effective communication training was also incorporated.
- Thereafter, I had been assigned to a Java based GUI project, where I have worked on hightech ADAS based navigation system for biggest automobile company. Develop solutions and make business decisions by collecting and processing data.

AUGUST 2021 - APRIL 2022

FREELANCE SEO EXECUTIVE, ACTIVE FITNESS STORE, UAE

My role here is mainly concentrated to off-page activities of their main website, which
includes backlink creation and optimization strategy formation, along with doing keyword
research and competitors' analysis followed by regular SEO audits.

OCTOBER-DECEMBER 2020

WEB DEVELOPER INTERN, UNHAD FOUNDATION (NGO)

 Working as a team, I have designed and developed the website for UNHADFOUNDATION, which is an NGO certified by Indian government.

JUNE 2020 – JUNE 2021

WEB DEVELOPER, MYGOVTSERVICE.COM

- I was responsible for managing and handling all the technical and development work of self-made website mygovtservice.com
- I also managed the SEO of the website, and was able to rank it on SERP.
- Due to its high performance, the website easily gets approved for Google AdSense.

JUNE-JULY 2019

JAVA TRAINEE, AKT SOFTWARE'S

• I have completed six weeks industrial project training from AKT Software's. In this project I worked upon the software development of "Automated Teller Machine", reforming my skills in Java, which also included Database Management of the software.

EDUCATION

JULY 2022-2024

MASTER OF COMPUTER APPLICATION, IGNOU

- I am currently pursuing the degree of MCA from Indra Gandhi National Open University.
- JULY 2018-2021
- **BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (HONORS)-COMPUTER SCIENCE,** ARYABHATTA

COLLEGE, DELHI UNIVERSITY

I have completed the degree of BSc. (H) Computer Science from Aryabhatta College, Delhi University.

CGPA: 7.67

SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, API.
- Database Management: SQL
- Version control: Git, GitHub
- Java (Basic)
- Software testing tool: Protractor
- Problem solving, WordPress Development, SEO

CERTIFICATIONS

July 2022 Problem Solving, Hacker Rank July 2022 SQL, Hacker Rank **July 2022** The complete JavaScript Course, 2022, Udemy May 2022 Software Testing: Learn Software Testing (Basic), Udemy **April 2021** The Complete 2022 Web Development Bootcamp, Udemy **MARCH 2021 GOOGLE ANALYTICS FOR BEGINNERS, Google Analytics FEBRUARY 2021** FUNDAMNETALS OF DIGITAL MARKETING, Google Digital Garage **OCTOBER 2020** MODERN WEB DEVELOPMENT, RLA College, Delhi University